### ALEX BAILON

Rosemead, CA 91770

Phone: (773)949-3259 | Email: abailon949@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/alex-bailon/">linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alex-bailon/</a> | Github: <a href="mailto:github.com/Alex-Bailon">github.com/Alex-Bailon</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:alex-bailon.github.io/">alex-bailon.github.io/</a>

#### SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in customer service ensuring that customers are always fully satisfied with the product and service they receive. Possesses strong analytical problem solving skills and adaptableness having worked alongside teams to efficiently create and develop mobile-first applications.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, Handlebars, React.js, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB

**Applications:** Github, Heroku, Postman, MySQL Workbench, Visual Studio Code, Xcode

### **P**ROJECTS

Home Body | Github: github.com/Alex-Bailon/health-app | Live: health-app-2020.herokuapp.com/

- Home Body is a health app that allows users to keep track of daily calorie, fat, sugar, and carb intake with all information being displayed in a doughnut chart.
- My responsibilities include working on backend server, route calls, user login using MySQL, and getting data to display on charts.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, JS, Chart.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Bcrypt.js, Passport, Express.

Flyte | Github: github.com/kyleres/Finance App | Live: kyleres.github.io/Finance App/

- Flyte is a finance app that gives users the ability to keep track of their investments.
- My core responsibilities include working on the JS to get API calls and bring the information to the page. Was responsible for bringing the front and back end together.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, Chart.js, Materialize, Github

Burger App | Github: github.com/Alex-Bailon/burger | Live: frozen-retreat-67912.herokuapp.com/

- An app that allows the user to input their favorite burgers, stores them into an MySQL database and with the click of a button "devours" the burger (update MySQL database).
- Developed this full stack app from scratch using the Model-View-Controller (MVC) model.
- Tools used: Express.js, node.js, ORM, MySQL, Handlebars.js, Materialize, Heroku

Weather App | github.com/Alex-Bailon/weather-dashboard | alex-bailon.github.io/weather-dashboard

- App allows users to input city names and get the current weather plus a five day forecast. The searched cities are added to local storage so the user may revisit the city's weather.
- Developed this front driven app from scratch.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, Materialize, Github

### EXPERIENCE

## Software Developer Fusion92

2020 | Freelance

Chicago, IL

Create and develop responsive emails and landing pages using MJML. Use Email on Acid to test and ensure generated HTML is fully responsive on all types of operating systems and email clients.

### Hospital Services Tech II LifeStream Blood Bank

2018 - 2019

Rosemead, CA

Managed, processed, transported and transferred blood products within a timely manner to ensure all hospitals were satisfied with the service they were receiving. Audited and ensured proper documentation were properly filled and compliant to FDA standards.

Service Banker 2017 – 2018 Bank of the West Alhambra, CA

Built rapport with customers while taking consideration of time. Ensured accurate customer transactions (deposits, withdrawals, wire transfers, ect.).

Fine Jewelry Clerical 2016 – 2017

Macy's Inc.

Acadia, CA

Received and merchandised inventory, ensuring all jewelry is properly displayed and organized and documents are accurately filled and in the proper location.

# Customer Service and Sales Representative Wells Fargo Bank, N.A

2015 – 2016 Alhambra, CA

Fulfilled the role of both teller and banker while providing excellent customer service. Opened new accounts, cross-sold consumer and business products, and maintained customer accounts.

### **Assistant Store Manager**

2012 - 2015

PLS Financial, Inc.

Chicago, IL

Developed new and current employees. Made weekly schedules, managed payrolls and completed store audits. Managed cash vault ensuring all cash is accounted for. Approved customer transactions.

### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: NorthWestern University, Evanston, IL

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.